Mommy?
Mommy, where are you?
Mom?
Suzume, are you up yet?
Yes.
There's a high-pressure system over Kyushu...
Looks delicious!
Don't forget your lunch today.
Okay.
Oh, and Suzume...
I'm going to be late tonight,
so figure out dinner on your own.
Eh?
Do you have a date, Tamaki?
Then, take all night!
It's overtime.
The "Fisherman Experience" event prep.
See you later.
Beautiful...
Hey...
you.
Do you know of any ruins in this area?
Ruins...?
I'm looking for a door.
Well, there's a little abandoned town
over by that mountain...
I see.
Thank you.
Huh?
Did you watch yesterday's livestream?
It was amazing!
Suzume!
Good morning.
Mornin', Aya.
Why's your face all red?
It is!? Seriously?
Yeah.
What's up?
I forgot something!
What!? You're gonna be late...
Why...
did I...?
TONAMI RESORT VISITOR'S GUIDE
DO NOT ENTER
This is it, right?
I can't think of any other "ruins."
Excuse me?
Hello?
Mister?
I feel like...
we've met somewhere before.
Am I totally stalking him right now?
I should go back.
He said something about a door.
Huh?
What is this?
What!?
Why...?
Huh?
What?
It's cold.
What the heck is going on!?
Creepy!
There you are.
To what do we owe the pleasure?
Lunch from your aunt?
I can taste the love from here.
Right...
Hey, you know those ruins by Kaminoura?
The old bathhouse district.
Really?
I remember it's in the mountains, right?
What about it?
There's this door...
Never mind.
For real!?
Gonna leave us hanging?
Spill the beans!
Wait...
Hey, is that a fire?
Where?
Over by the mountains.
Huh? Where?
Look at the smoke!
What are you talking about?
Do you see anything, Aya?
Nope.
But...
Is it from the fields?
It's right there.
W-What!?
EARTHQUAKE WARNING
An earthquake?
Intensity 4.0!
Do you feel it?
Oh, it's shaking.
Hey, an earthquake.
Really?
I'm wide open!
Let's go!
What was that?
Think we're okay.
Is it over?
That was nothing.
That was a little scary...
The warning was a bit much.
Hey...
Look...
over there.
What are you talking about?
Suzume, are you okay?
They can't see it?
Hey, Suzume!
Daddy!
Why can't anyone...?
What is that thing?
Don't tell me...
It can't be!
There's no way!
It's that door!
It's him!
What are you doing!?
Get out of here!
Are you all right?
What now?
This is...
...not good.
Earthquake warning.
Dammit!
Watch out!
Get away from here!
Dammit...
Why are—
You need to close this, right?
O Divine Gods who dwell beneath this land...
You have long protected us for generations...
Thy mountains and rivers...
that we have long called our own...
Dad! C'mon, hurry! Over here!
What's...!?
Haven't been to a bathhouse in a while.
Mom, let's take a bath again!
Honey, are you having another drink?
Let's come again next year. On a family trip!
It's closed!
I return to thee!
What was that?
The Keystone was supposed to keep this place sealed.
What?
Why did you come here?
How can you see the worm?
Where is the Keystone!?
Worm?
Stone?
What are you talking about?
This place became a Gate.
The worm comes through the Gate.
Thank you for helping me.
Now, forget everything you saw here and go home.
But...
Wait! Your arm!
MIYAZAKI BROADCASTING
That was a pretty big earthquake.
Look at these shingles...
I think we got off pretty light.
Please go upstairs.
I'll get the first aid kit.
That's really not—
If you won't go to the hospital,
at least let me bandage it.
Is he some kinda man-baby?
HOW TO BECOME A NURSE
A child's chair.
Around 1:20PM this afternoon
there was an earthquake in Miyazaki
with a recorded magnitude of 6.3.
There is no risk of a tsunami at this time.
We do not have any information regarding injuries—
You know your stuff.
My mom was a nurse.
But first...
I have a ton of questions.
Figures.
You said "worm." What did you mean?
The worm is a giant force that dwells
beneath the Japanese islands.
It has no rhyme or reason.
Yet, it rages and shakes the land if disturbed.
But you just beat it, right?
I only shut it away temporarily.
If we don't seal it with the Keystone, it'll appear again.
You mean there'll be another earthquake?
It's my job to stop that from happening.
Your job...
Hey, who exactly are yo—
Thanks for patching me up.
My name's Souta Munakata.
Oh, uh...
I-I'm Suzume Iwato.
A cat?
Oh my gosh, this kitten's a toothpick.
One sec.
You must've been starving.
That earthquake was scary, huh?
So cute.
Want to become my cat?
Yeah.
Eh?
Suzume
is kind.
I like you.
You...
are in the way.
W-W-Whaaa—?!
Souta? Where are you?
What the...
...hell!?
Whaaaaa—!?
S-Souta?
Suzume...
What's happening?
Is this your doing!?
Come back here!
Dammit!
Wait, wait, wait...
This can't be happening!
No no no no!
Oh, Suzume.
Tamaki!
Sorry, stepping out!
Where are you going?
I came home early, worried about you.
The earthquake!?
You didn't pick up your phone.
Sorry! Missed it.
But, I'm okay.
H-Hey...
Suzume! Answer me!
Hey, a kitty!
What is that?
Excuse me!
What is even happening right now?
Hey, Suzume!
Hey!
Where...
are you going!?
What the—
Give me a...
I'm so sorry!
Thank you very much for your patience.
We have been given clearance to depart.
We are now disembarking from the dock.
Hey, did you see that?
Yeah, I did.
What the heck was that?
A toy?
NO PETS
You see that chair?
Very impressive.
Where...
did you go!?
My gosh!
Why do you run!?
What did you do to me!?
What are you!?
Answer me!
Oh no!
Suzume!
See you.
Whaaaaat!?
Like I said...
I'm spending the night at Aya's.
I'm sorry.
I'll be home tomorrow.
Now wait just one moment, Suzume.
You can stay over,
but why is the first aid kit in your room?
Did you have someone over?
I don't even want to think about it, but...
Are you seeing some good-for-noth—!
No!
No boys! I'm hanging up!
Did you see that runnin' chair, missy?
No.
Souta.
This ship will reach Ehime by morning.
Looks like the cat's ship is heading there too.
I see.
I got some bread.
Thanks.
But I'm not hungry.
Okay.
Um, why are you a chair?
Apparently, that cat placed a curse on me.
A curse!?
Are you okay?
Does it hurt?
I'm fine.
You're warm.
Still, I have to figure this out.
Souta, there's something bothering me.
A relic in the ruins?
That's the Keystone!
You removed it?
Removed?
Of course...
That cat is the Keystone!
How dare it leave its post.
What do you mean?
You set the Keystone free, and now it's cursed me.
Oh no...
I'm so sorry, I...
What should I do?
No.
It's my fault for not finding the door sooner.
This isn't on you.
But...
Suzume, I'm a Closer.
A "Closer"?
I close the open doors so that disaster won't spread.
I travel across Japan doing that.
It's our job as Closers.
You're hungry, right?
Eat up.
We must turn the Keystone back and banish the worm.
Surely then, I'll return to my body.
So, don't worry.
Tomorrow, you're going home.
Mommy?
Mommy!
Mommy!!
Where are you!?
Souta?
Do you always sleep like that?
My heart's pounding.
Thank you very much for riding the Shikoku Orange Ferry today.
Man it's hot.
Finally!
You're goin' to Osaka?
It's been a while.
Yeah, but I'll spend the night somewhere.
On behalf of the entire crew, we hope to see you again.
Suzume?
Finally, you are up!
You wouldn't wake up,
I was beginning to think this was all a dream.
I was asleep?
Never mind.
Now, how do we find that cat?
We should ask around the harbor first.
Eh?
But where are we?
Hey, you!
It looks like...
the edge of Ehime?
Wow, we came a long way.
Get on the next ferry, and you can make it home tonight.
You should—
Oh no!
What is it!?
OMG! I FEEL LIKE I'M IN "WHISPER OF THE HEART"
Hey, a white cat.
It's so cute!
A kitten?
What's your name?
Who are you?
And you are?
Perhaps "Daijin"?
Daijin?
You do seem pretty fancy.
IT'S SO ADORABLE... SITTING NEXT TO ME.
#WithDaijin
This is so him, isn't it?
How could this be...
LOOK WHO I MET
GETTING OFF THE TRAIN
CONDUCTING!
SNACK TIME
INSTAGRAM-ABLE
LOOKING SLY!!
"Daijin"?
I mean he does kind of...
He's moving by train.
I have to go after him.
Thanks for everything, Suzume.
This is goodbye.
Get home safely.
Umm...
Your family's going to worry if you don't go home.
It's fine. They let me make my own choices.
This could be very dangerous.
It's not safe for you to follow me.
I think you've got bigger problems right now.
Look.
I JUST SAW SOMETHING CRAZY!
I SAW IT TOO!
MYSTERY GIRL AND MOVING CHAIR
NEW ROBOT FROM BOST*N DYNAMICS!?
SEND ME INFO!
Oh no...
It's dangerous for you to walk in public.
Someone's gonna catch you before you catch the cat.
Guess I've got no choice...
Suzume...
Until we find the Keystone...
I'll need your help.
My pleasure.
"DAIJIN" APPEARS ON TANGERINE FARM
#WithDaijin
Souta.
Oh crap!
Whaaa—!?
Hold that side.
Oh, right.
No way...
You're a lifesaver!
Thanks so much!
It was nothing.
You're like a wizard.
How'd ya do that?
My body reacted before I could think... I guess?
Oh?
Well, amazin' either way.
I'm Chika. A junior in high school.
Me too!
I'm Suzume.
Your uniform... You're not from 'round here, are ya?
Oh, right.
You came all the way from Kyushu to look for a cat!?
Yeah.
Is it yours?
Not exactly.
Hey, this photo...
I think it's near here.
What's the matter?
Suzume?
Sorry, I just remembered something.
Hey, whaddya mean?
Suzume!?
Can the worm show up anywhere?
The Gate in this area has opened.
We need to close it fast.
We're not going to make it at this rate.
Oh no!
Hey!
Suzume!
Chika?
Dunno what's goin' on, but you're in a rush, yeah?
Get on!
You sure this is the way?
Few years back, there was a landslide.
There's nothin' past here.
It's abandoned?
That's perfect. Keep going!
Will there be another quake?
We must close the door before the worm falls to the earth.
Or else...
DO NOT ENTER
Here's fine!
What?
Thanks so much, Chika!
Huh? S-Suzume?
Suzume, you've done enough.
Hey, wait! Souta!
It's too dangerous.
Go back with that girl.
You can't go with that body!
I have to.
KASUGA MIDDLE SCHOOL
The school's become a Gate.
Dammit.
I can't even...
No!
It's falling.
Souta!
Suzume!?
Are you not afraid to die!?
I'm not!
Suzume?
You lock the door.
Close your eyes and think of the people who lived here.
The keyhole will appear.
You're telling me this now!?
Please! I can't do it!
Close your eyes!
Now feel all the emotion that should be here.
Listen to their voices.
Mornin'!
G'morning.
I've got exams tomorrow.
Man, it's hot!
We can't lose the next match!
Come hang out after you graduate.
O Divine Gods who dwell beneath this land...
You have long protected us for generations...
Thy mountains and rivers...
that we have long called our own...
Now!
I return to thee!
We did it, Suzume.
You just prevented an earthquake.
Really?
I can't believe it...
I did it!
We make a great team!
Suzume, you're amazing.
Another Gate will open.
The Keystone.
Wait!
Did he open the door?
You're in Ehime?
Suzume, you said you were staying at Aya's yesterday.
"A little vacation"?
Not funny at all.
I had better see you home tomorrow.
Where are you staying tonight?
Minoru, we got a table.
Go ahead. I'll catch up.
I'll invite Tamaki.
That's NOT what I'm talking about!
What about school?
Suzume going through a rebellious phase?
Anyway!
Tell me where you're staying tonight.
And, I really hope you're alone, young lady.
Minoru...
Something on my face?
Oh, Shige made a reservation...
Huh? Where did—!?
Honestly...
SORRY FOR HANGING UP
I'M GOOD!
I PROMISE TO COME HOME SAFELY!
PLEASE DON'T WORRY!
*BOW*
READ
Yes?
I brought ya dinner.
Eh?
Wow, thank you!
Mind if I join ya, Suzume?
Not at all!
Could you give me a sec?
What do we do?
You two enjoy yourselves.
Looks like this body doesn't get hungry.
INN - AMABE
Let's eat!
It tastes sooo good...
Um, are you cryin'?
It just tastes so good.
You must've been starvin'.
For some reason we just had a ton of customers today.
Sorry to keep you waitin'.
No, not at all!
You're the one putting me up tonight.
With a bath, yukata, and food!
NEW MESSAGE
Ugh.
Who is it?
My aunt.
Oh man...
She seriously needs a date.
Your aunt's single?
How old is she?
About 40, I think?
She's really pretty, though.
It's just the two of us.
She's my guardian.
Sounds complicated.
Not really.
But sometimes...
I feel like I've stolen her most precious years.
Especially lately.
You sound like her ex-boyfriend.
Oh my gosh!
I wish she'd just leave the nest already.
Speakin' of ex-boyfriends...
Suzume, you ever dated anyone?
Me? No...
Mmm-hmm, that's the best thing for ya.
Nothin' good comes from datin' guys.
Were you going out with someone, Chika?
You wanna hear?
Not again!
Why don't you clean the bath next?
You're kidding!
He didn't!
Oh, totally.
Not just that...
Whaaa—!? For real?
Right? Boys are dumb.
I got to go there again today thanks to you.
My middle school was over there.
After the landslide a few years ago
they abandoned the whole area.
Hey, Suzume.
What were you doin' there?
Covered in mud and all...
And what's with that chair?
Who exactly are ya?
That chair...is a memento from my mom.
But now...
Sorry, it's hard to explain.
Suzume, you're like a wizard.
Full o' secrets.
But why do I feel like...
you're doing somethin' really important?
Thank you, Chika!
Yeah, I think I'm doing something important, too!
Modest much?
Some people just refuse to wake up.
Who? Your BF?
I don't have one!
I mean in general.
If they won't wake up...
just give 'em a kiss.
Wha—!?
I heard you're headin' home?
Yes, I am!
Thank you so much for everything.
You're welcome anytime, y'hear?
Thank you!
Hey, check it out!
This guy's amazin'!
It is unknown where this kitty came from,
but he's crossing the cables of a suspension bridge.
Uhhh...
Ain't that somethin'?
Hey, Souta!
Wake up already!
Ugh.
Wait.
Where's your mouth?
Suzume?
Good morning.
What is it?
Don't "What is it" me!
Look, it's Daijin.
This kitty is creating a lot of buzz...
What's he trying to do?
Gods follow naught but their own whims, so...
Gods?
That bridge leads to Kobe.
We should—
Suzume.
You're leavin' soon, right?
Yeah, just getting dressed.
Perfect.
Use these, if ya want.
Yup. Suits ya better than me.
Ya stuck out in your uniform with that chair.
Chika...
How can I ever repay you?
Don't worry nothin' 'bout it.
Come visit sometime?
Yeah.
I promise.
TO KOBE
Suzume...
You need to be clearer about what you want.
Like waving your arms or something.
You do it and people will be shocked and stop.
Chairs shouldn't be moving.
Thank goodness.
You do get it.
Can we go by bus?
The next bus is six hours from now.
Suzume.
You said this chair was a memento of your mother?
Yeah.
Why does it only have three legs?
I was so young, I don't really remember.
But, I lost this chair once.
When I found it, a leg was missing.
Where you headed?
Won't be any buses for a while.
Sounds fun.
A little soul searching?
Going to downtown Kobe?
That would be amazing.
Got it.
We were visiting their grandma's
and were on our way back to Kobe.
You really lucked out.
Mom, look at this!
What is it?
Stop touching her stuff!
Okaaaay.
Sorry.
It's fine.
Why are they staring at your stuff?
It's just a chair.
I see.
Still staring...
EHIME
TOKUSHIMA
KOBE
Careful!
Don't spill anything.
Keep her chair nice and clean.
I know!
You bet'cha!
Didn't know you could see it from here...
The amusement park.
An amusement park?
Over there, on the mountain.
My folks would take me there when I was little.
But things went downhill.
Now, they don't even have the money to tear it down.
There's lots of lonely places like that these days.
I don't believe it...
The kids' daycare just texted
saying they had to close today.
Hey, knock it off!
Ugh, I have to open the shop soon.
Gotta find someone...
Oh!
Hm?
Huuuuuh!?
KYUNOMIYA SUJI STRIP MALL
Umm...
What do you want to play?
House!
Let's make curry!
Ready...
Go!
Whaaa—!?
Don't eat those!
Whoever empties it first wins.
Ready? Go!
Stop that!
You're Mt. Fuji, 'kay?
Ready? Go!
I don't think...
...I'm cut out for kids.
You need help.
What the—!?
Heeeeey! Isn't it amazing?
What a super cool toy.
[BAR HARBOR]
Whoooooa!
Wooooow!
Me too! Me too!
My turn next!
Not you.
It talked!
P-Pretty cool, huh?
It's a chair-shaped robot...with built-in AI?
What's its name?
Souta.
Souta, what's tomorrow's weather!?
Souta, play music!
Souta, a word game!
Souta, are the stocks up today!?
Souta's not that smart, so...
What was that, Suzume?
It spoke again!
Running away from home?
I mean, I did it when I was a kid too.
When you're at that age,
the town, your parents... it's suffocating.
So—
We're not talking about you.
Right.
Where is she going?
What did I do wrong?
She keeps putting me off.
Won't even tell me where she's staying tonight.
What about her phone's GPS?
I don't have access.
What about her bank account?
Is it linked to her phone?
Where is she?
She's in Kobe...
Kobe?
TRANSACTION HISTORY
That's a long way from home.
I can't let her be alone anymore...
Um, Tamaki?
If there's anything else I can do—
Minoru.
I'm taking the day off tomorrow.
What?
Then, I'm taking the day off, too.
Why? You need to work.
Right...
Suzume.
Can you come down?
Okay!
Whoa!
Rumi, you look gorgeous.
Like a different person, huh?
The kids all good?
Yup. Sound asleep.
Then, you can give me a hand over here.
It's never this crowded...
Ma'am.
She's the help?
Yep!
What!?
Welcome!
You don't have to work the floor.
Got it.
Wash these. Quick.
O-Okay.
Ice, please!
Coming!
Two wine glasses.
Huh?
No, the ones next to those.
Right.
[NOW HIRING HOSTESSES]
Welcome!
Suzume, three hot towels.
Okay!
Ow!
Where's the bottle?
I'm...
For Sasaki.
R-Right...
I had too much to drink. And it was all your fault...
How endearing it is from a tender young lady...
You're awfully young, aren't you?
Come drink with an old lady.
Why don't we sing a duet?
Really? So ya like 'em young, do ya?
Why, thank you!
Miki? You got us there.
Oh well.
What do you mean, "Oh well"?
Hey, Daijin!
Another glass!
Wha—!?
Daijin, you big spender.
You rock!
You go!
This isn't happening...
U-Umm... That seat over there.
Hm? Oh, he's a first-time customer.
C-Customer—
He's quiet but getting along with regulars already.
Um, but doesn't he look a bit...
...cat-like?
You think so?
Seems pretty refined to me.
Seriously!?
Oh, welcome!
Sorry, but gotta go!
Souta!
It's Daijin!
Hey, just what are you—!?
Suzume. How you doin'?
What?
Look.
Over there.
The worm.
Daijin!
Suzume!
We need to go.
Yeah!
Is it an earthquake?
Huh? Really?
Hey, Miki. Where's Suzume?
It's the amusement park!
NOTICE OF CLOSURE
THANK YOU FOR 40 AMAZING YEARS
The Ferris wheel!
It's become a Gate!
Souta, look!
Daijin.
I'm going to catch Daijin and turn him back to a Keystone!
While I do that, you...
Yeah.
Close the door and lock it.
I can do this.
Get the door!
Okay!
I can make it!
My body...
I can really move!
I'm getting used to this!
I won't fail again.
Suzume.
You're goood!
Daijin!
Today, you will turn me back!
Look! The lights are on.
Why?
Wasn't it abandoned?
What?
Wh-Wh-Whoa—!
Wait!
Seriously!?
Mom?
Become the Keystone, and seal that worm!
The Eastern Pillar alone will not hold.
Can't...
Why!?
I've entrusted this duty to you.
What does that mean?
You go away.
Daijin's gonna play with Suzume.
With Suzume?
Suzume!
What happened, Suzume!?
What's going on?
What do you see?
Suzume!? Come back.
You mustn't go in!
Suzume!
Suzume, you're inside a Ferris wheel!
Wake up! You're going to fall!
Dammit.
O Divine Gods who dwell beneath this land...
You have long protected us for generations...
Thy mountains and rivers...
that we have long called our own...
Whoa, it's so high up! Cool!
Don't have too much fun now.
We should come here again, together!
This is our anniversary. Let's come back.
An amusement park on our first date is so cliché!
Daddy, let's come back again!
Suzume! Come!
Souta?
O Divine Gods who dwell beneath this land...
You have long protected us for generations...
Thy mountains and rivers...
that we have long called our own...
Now!
I return to you!
Where's Daijin?
Gone. Again.
Let's go inside.
What's wrong?
I was so scared!
You were amazing.
Thank you.
Suzume...
What were you looking at, beyond the Gate?
Wha—
A bright night sky filled with stars and fields...
The Ever-After.
So you can see it!?
"Ever-After"?
This world's other half, where the worm dwells.
And, where all time exists simultaneously.
I could see it, but I couldn't go in.
The Ever-After is where all souls go to rest.
It's not somewhere the living can reach.
Not a place we're supposed to go.
The troublemaker's back.
Suzume, where were you!?
Oh, um... I'm sorry.
You had me worried sick! Running off at this hour.
Well, she's all right, isn't she?
But—!
How many times have we run away from home?
Why don't we have a bite for now.
Sorry...
How about fried udon?
Yeah! With a sunny side up on top.
And tuna-mayo!
Yeah.
And you, Suzume?
We actually put potato salad on top.
Say what?
On fried udon?
O-M-G.
Think about the calories.
Sooo hungry.
Thanks for the meal!
Delish!
I'll gain some weight.
Needs a beer!
Should we?
After drinking all night?
Sure, why not?
Join us, Souta.
Didn't expect the potato salad, though.
I'm making this for my boyfriend.
H-Hey!
What boyfriend?
I'll have one in no time.
What's with that chair?
Adorable.
A kid's chair?
Why are you on it?
A Kobe souvenir...?
You're not making any sense.
They must've thought you were weird.
Really?
Do you travel like this all the time?
Not all the time.
I have a flat in Tokyo.
After college, I plan to be a teacher.
What!? You're a university student?
Yeah?
And...a job!?
What about this job!?
Being a Closer has been in my family for generations.
I'll continue that.
But it doesn't put food on the table.
I see...
But it's an important job.
Most important jobs, people shouldn't see.
I need to get back into my own body.
So I can continue this and become a teacher.
But... I'm already...
Perhaps, I'm...
already...
It's getting farther.
The light grows dimmer.
And so do the voices.
My body...
My mind...
It's so...
Cold.
I'm so cold.
Cold...
So cold...
Am I...
Is this where...
I meet my end?
Souta?
Souta!?
Good morning.
Took you long enough.
Hey, there's another photo of Daijin.
See?
Suzume.
Did...
Did you just do something to me?
Nope.
The Chugoku Expressway south towards Okayama...
I was counting on you to help me at the bar tonight, too.
Here, this is for you.
You look even more like a runaway child now.
Rumi, thank you so much for everything.
Mmhmm.
Just be sure to send word to your guardian.
I will.
Ah, crap!
I totally forgot about Tamaki.
55...unread messages?
She's coming to get me?
Suzume, you can make the next train.
Buy a ticket. Hurry!
The bullet train?
We know where Daijin is, so...
It's the quickest way, right?
To Tokyo, though?
That'll take all my savings.
You better pay me back, Mr. College Man.
I gotcha.
Souta, look!
What is it?
This train is so fast.
Cool!
Yeah...it's fast.
We will soon arrive at Atami. The doors on the...
Souta, did we just...
What's wrong?
Did we just miss Mt. Fuji?
Look!
Why didn't you say something!?
Ahh, right...
I wanted to see it...
Sorry...
We'll soon be arriving at Tokyo.
Tokyo. This is the final stop.
That way, Suzume.
Okay!
Right.
Left.
Go up.
Train on the left.
Run!
Get off, next stop.
What!?
Why do I feel like your horse?
Before Daijin, there's a place I want to go.
Could you make a call?
Welcome!
Um, my name is Iwato.
I just phoned...
Oh, right.
Souta's relative.
I heard about you.
Here's the key to his room.
Room 301.
Take your time.
Well, aren't you popular, Souta?
What?
When is he coming back from his trip?
It's a bit lonely without him.
He's so sweet and cute!
And gorgeous.
Don't take them seriously...
Really...
Welcome.
Scuse me...
I want to look something up.
See the cardboard box on top of the shelf?
Grab it for me.
Sure.
Oof...
Souta, can I step on you?
Ask that before you do it!
SECRET ARTS OF CLOSERS VOL.1
Is this...
the worm?
Yeah.
And this is the Keystone.
The Western Pillar.
And the Eastern Pillar.
Then does that mean...
...there are two Keystones.
Disasters that couldn't be contained by closing the Gate
were sealed away using the Keystones.
So...
The locations change era to era.
The Keystone from Kyushu is now running around as Daijin.
Yeah.
The other Keystone is here.
In Tokyo.
Keeping the worm's head at bay.
What I want to know is exactly where...
Where in Tokyo it is.
Apparently, there's a huge Gate there too.
It opened 100 years ago and decimated the Kanto region.
And was shut by the Closers of that time.
Tokyo's Gate.
CLOSER'S JOURNAL
Perhaps Daijin is trying to open that door once more.
It's no use...
The information has been blotted out.
Why?
Is the location a secret?
I've gotta ask Grandpa.
Grandpa?
He pretty much raised me.
He's in a hospital nearby.
I didn't want to disappoint him...
looking like this.
Souta, you in there?
I know you are.
The window's open.
It's Serizawa.
Of all the times...
Wh-Who?
Someone I know.
Just make him go away.
Souta! I'm opening the door, dude.
I'm coming in.
I warned ya.
He's a good guy.
Hello.
Um, and you are?
His younger sister.
He's got a sister?
Well... A cousin who's like a younger sister, really.
What?
Umm...
You're Serizawa, right?
Teacher employment exam?
Yeah.
Yesterday was the second one, but he didn't show up.
He had a test yesterday?
What an idiot...
TEACHER EMPLOYMENT EXAM PREP
Four years right down the drain.
It bothered me so much, I couldn't focus on my test.
Say, you...
Suzume, was it?
When you get a hold of Souta,
tell him that I'm pissed, and that he's dead to me.
Ah, wait.
He owes me 20,000 yen.
I want that first.
I heard his family business was in trouble and all...
But, he doesn't take care of himself enough.
Ticks me off.
See ya.
EARTHQUAKE WARNING
Is there gonna be a quake?
Hey, what are you—
It stopped...
You okay?
It's close.
Whoa, that's a lot of birds.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Hey, where are you going?
I had no idea.
About your test!
What do we do?
It's not your fault!
But it's all because I freed the Keystone!
We put an end to it today.
We return the cat to the Keystone, and I become human again.
What's going on?
So many birds!
Because of the earthquake?
Hey, where's the Gate!?
Yeah.
Looks like it's downriver.
Oh my.
A cat?
Suzume!
Let's play.
Daijin!
H-Hey!
What was that?
A chair!?
Did you see that?
What was it?
What?
Daijin!
Return to the Keystone!
One is not enough!
Nope.
Why!?
You still don't get it?
Where'd you go!?
Souta?
Tokyo's Gate is...
down there?
How do we even get there!?
It stopped?
No.
What the...
It's no use...
Earthquake warning.
EARTHQUAKE WARNING
The warning stopped.
What's going on?
The second Keystone...
Wha—
It couldn't hold it.
The whole body is coming out!
Daijin!?
We will prevent a major earthquake.
Suzume.
I'm going.
You can't be serious!
Souta!
Hey, is that...?
Wait!
No way!
Suzume!?
What's going on?
What's that?
Something's weird...
Are you crazy!?
But...
Suzume!!
I'm coming!
Souta?
The surface is unstable.
Don't let go.
Okay.
EARTHQUAKE EPICENTER THE 23 DISTRICTS
The worm...
is covering the city.
Souta!
I know!
We need to pierce it with the Keystone...
with Daijin.
Suzume!
When the worm falls...
the earth will break.
Daijin!
Souta?
What's the matter?
A lot of people...
are about to die.
Why would you let that happen!?
Become the Keystone again!
Can't.
I'm no longer the Keystone.
You are the Keystone.
Hey!
What should we do, Souta?
Souta?
Suzume... I'm sorry.
I finally understand.
I didn't realize...
or maybe didn't want to.
Wait, Souta?
Your body...
Now...
It's freezing!
I am...
the Keystone.
The moment I became a chair,
the role of a Keystone was passed on to me.
That can't be...
This is it...
This is where I end?
Souta?
But, I was able to meet you.
Souta? Souta!?
Hey! Souta!
Souta!?
That's not Souta anymore.
Daijin...
How dare you!
Aren't you going to stick that into the worm?
How could I!?
The worm's gonna fall.
The earth will break.
It's falling...
Souta!
Please, wake up!
That's not Souta anymore!
Souta, wake up!
What am I supposed to do?
Souta!?
SOUTA!
Lots'a people are gonna die.
History will repeat...
I don't...
I never wanted this...
How can this...
Hey, look at that!
Wow!
Aurora?
Rainbow at night?
Beautiful...
Mommy!
Is it ready yet?
Not even close.
Now?
Not yet.
Hmm, almost?
Nooow?
Let's see...
Here you go!
Happy birthday, Suzume.
Whoooa.
Hey, is its face here?
What?
This is a chair.
Just for you.
How's that?
A chair for me!
Thank you, Mommy!
I'm gonna keep it
forever and ever!
Forever?
Well, thank goodness I built it for you.
MAY 24: TODAY MY MOM BUILT ME A CHAIR...
How long...
did I actually care for it?
Where...
...am I?
Souta?
Is this...?
Tokyo's Gate!?
Souta!?
I can't get in.
He's in the Ever-After.
Souta.
Souta?
Souta!
Suzume?
Finally, just the two of us!
This is all your fault!
Give me Souta back!
Can't.
Why?
He's not human anymore.
Then make him human!
Suzume, that hurts.
Bring him back now!
I said that hurts!
You—!
You don't love me?
What?!
How could I!?
You love me, right?
I hate—!
Go away.
Don't ever talk to me again.
Suzume doesn't love me...
I promise, I'll come save you.
I return to you...
What?
Hey, look at that girl.
She's not wearing any shoes.
You're right. Ew.
Just look at her clothes.
That girl over there.
Is she barefoot?
For real?
Munakata's condition has stabilized.
Yeah, it was pretty bad yesterday.
HITSUJIRO MUNAKATA
Souta's...
Souta failed, didn't he?
I-I'm sorry for barging in...
I heard from Souta that you were in the hospital.
Did he drag you into this?
What is the fate of my grandson?
He became a Keystone and went to the Ever-After...
I see.
I saw the worm from my window yesterday.
I wanted nothing more than to go myself...
but this old body of mine wouldn't listen.
That's why I want to know how to enter the Ever-After.
Why?
Huh? Because... we have to save Souta!
That isn't necessary.
What?
Souta will spend decades now
as a Keystone housing the gods.
He is no longer of our realm.
How could...
But there must be a way to—
Are you trying to waste my grandson's sacrifice?
What?
Who is the one who pierced the worm?
Did you, with Souta?
But that was...
Answer me!
It was me!
I see.
That's fine!
If you didn't, millions would have died!
Take pride in your deed, keep your mouth shut,
and return to whence you came!
This world is not for the ordinary.
Forget everything that happened.
How could I forget?
I'll open the underground Gate again.
What!? What are you saying?
I have to get in!
Impossible.
You cannot enter it there!
You mustn't open the Gate!
Wait!
The Ever-After is a beautiful place.
But it is the domain of the departed.
Does that not scare you?
It doesn't.
Whether one lives or dies is a matter of luck.
I've always felt that way.
But...
I'm afraid of a world without Souta.
There is but one Gate through which
people may traverse in their lifetime.
You've been to the Ever-After before, no?
What did you see there?
That was...
A young version of myself.
And, my mom...who passed away.
I suspect you got lost in
the Ever-After when you were young.
You must find that Gate. From back then.
It has been far too long.
I see you are finally unbound.
Do you wish to follow that girl?
I entrust everything to you.
I'm borrowing your shoes, Souta.
Hey!
Hey, you!
Suzume!
Serizawa?
Where are you going?
To find Souta?
To find a door.
What?
Sorry, I'm in a hurry.
Hey, I looked everywhere for you!
What are—
The cousin thing's a lie, right?
Why does it matter?
Get in.
What?
You're going after Souta, right?
Then, I'll take you.
Why would you—
I'm worried about my friend, okay!?
What's that?
A fight?
There you are!
Suzume!!
W-What? Tamaki?
Do you have any idea how worried I've been!?
And you! You stay away from her.
Or I'll call the police.
Who're you?
Is this the guy who came to our house?
Whatever he told you is a lie.
We're going.
I'm sorry, but I can't yet.
Suzume!
Serizawa, let's go.
O-Okay.
H-Hey!
Suzume!
What the heck is wrong with you!?
I can't let you go alone.
Tamaki, get out.
Come here, Suzume.
This car has doors, you know!
Is he two-timing?
Men are such pigs.
Let's all calm dow—
Yeah, and you ignored them!
Are you guys...
done yet?
Daijin?
A cat spoke!?
What? Of course not...
Yeah, you're right.
Sure, cats don't talk.
More importantly...
Destination confirmed.
Serizawa, can you take us here?
W-Whaaat!? This is far!
Suzume, isn't this...?
You said you would take me, didn't you?
Please, I have to go there.
Seriously...
Guess we're not comin' back tonight...
What are you trying to pull?
♪ In order to see his mom...
♪ I boarded the train all on my own!
♪ ...the twilit cityscape and cars passing by
♪ I watched out the corner of my eye.
Do you mind?
What? This is the perfect road trip song.
And we have a cat...
Suzume's not listening.
She's asleep.
Hey, is that cat hers?
We don't have any cats.
Serizawa...
You're a teacher in training?
Um, yeah...
I wanna become one.
Is this car okay?
It's used. I got it super cheap.
Cool, huh?
Are you sure you want to do this?
It's more than seven hours one way.
Your daughter's not the only one looking for Souta.
She's not my daughter...
She's my niece.
My older sister passed away, so I took her in.
She was a single mom.
I see.
Back then, Suzume was only four.
She couldn't process her mother disappearing so suddenly...
and got lost trying to search for her.
Suzume!
Suzume, where are you?
Suzume!!
Auntie?
Everything's all right now.
I'm so sorry it took me so long to find you.
Starting today, you're my daughter, okay?
It's been 12 years since that day.
I took her with me to Kyushu,
and we've lived together ever since.
Oh, do you mind the smoke?
It's your car.
So, we're headed for Suzume's hometown then?
Is Souta really gonna be there?
I don't know...
But there's nothing left there.
Say, why don't we head back to Tokyo?
That'll make her give up.
Souta owes me money, and I need it back.
So you're a loan shark now?
♪ And she'll be so mad at you, my darling!
CONTAMINATED SOIL
EVACUATION ZONE AHEAD
♪ I guess it's the pain that brings back those memories
♪ All of the ones that I Thought were all dead and gone
Did you just feel something shake?
Look who decided to join us.
Now your aunt's asleep.
Does your family not know how to sleep?
EARTHQUAKE WARNING INTENSITY 3.0
You're right. I didn't realize it.
Stop!
Hey, wa—!
Suzume!
It's not appearing.
Souta must be containing it.
Daijin...
What are you trying to do?
Why won't you say anything?
Hey, can anyone...
become a Keystone?
Not just Closers?
Heeey!
Suzume.
What's up with you?
Sorry, it's nothing.
Gotta hurry.
We're about halfway now.
I didn't know this area was so beautiful.
This place is...beautiful?
Sorry, we need to get going.
Hey.
Hey, you...
Cat!
Hey!
Man...
Your family's got some serious issues...
♪ What is it you're looking for?
♪ Something hard to find?
♪ In your bag, through your desk
♪ you looked but can't find it.
♪ Do you want to keep searching?
♪ Why not dance with me instead?
♪ Into our dreams, on into our dreams.
♪ Wouldn't you rather roam a bit?
Rain?
Seriously?
Well, that's not good...
Why? You have a roof, don't you?
Just close it.
Let's give it a go.
Hey...
Yep, still broken.
Haha.
Don't "Haha" me!
How're you gonna fix this!?
No worries.
We're almost to the next rest stop.
Approximately 40km to your destination. ETA 35 minutes.
Almost, my foot!
OYA KAIGAN - REST STOP
The time is 3:30PM.
Thanks for the grub!
What?
You're with some shady playboy?
Well, more like a discount hustler,
but I don't think he's up to anything.
That's super dangerous!
It's just you two girls.
A closed car's dangerous!
Well, it's a convertible.
That's even worse!
Tamaki, where in Miyagi are you now?
Tamaki again?
Yes, got it.
Minoru doesn't give up, does he?
Wait one sec.
There's a bus at that rest stop headed for Tokyo.
And there are open seats.
I can book 'em right now.
Just hold up, Minoru.
We've come quite a ways...
I don't think that...
EARTHQUAKE WARNING INTENSITY 3.0
Souta.
Souta...
Suzume, it just shook again, huh?
There are so many earthquakes lately.
Hey, you sure you don't want anything to eat?
Yup.
Suzume...
Could you tell me?
What?
Why are you so hell-bent on returning home?
A door...
Sorry, it's hard to explain.
What's that mean?
After all the trouble you've caused!
Trouble?
You wouldn't understand anyway, Tamaki.
That's it. We're taking that bus home.
You won't tell me anything.
You look depressed.
You won't eat.
Let me go!
Suzume!
You go home, Tamaki!
I never asked you to come after me!
Do you have any idea!?
I was worried sick!
That's exactly why I'm suffocating!
I can't...take this anymore.
I had to take you in.
I devoted the last 10 years to you.
I'm such an idiot...
Every day I walk on eggshells.
A child who lost her mother?
I could never have anyone over because of you.
And who would marry someone who's basically got a kid?
Even with my sister's money, there's no balancing that scale.
Is that...?
But it's not like I...
Sorry it took me so long...
had a choice, either.
You're my daughter...
You're the one who said, "You're my daughter"!
I don't remember that.
Get out of my house.
Give me back my life!
Who... are you?
Sadaijin.
Sadaijin?
H-Hey, Tamaki?
What happened!?
Are you okay?
What did I...
Sorry, I have to—
Serizawa.
Yeah?
I think I'm losing it...
Why would I say something like that?
Uh...
Hey, hey, hey!
Are you okay?
Yup... Seriously big issues.
♪ I took the button on my uniform...
Nope.
♪ A Valentine's day kiss!
Not this.
STOP FIGHTING
There ya go.
♪ Please stop the fighting, both of you...
♪ I don't want you two... to fight over me
This car's pretty great when it's sunny, right?
Umm... Do you mind?
Huh?
I'm choosing the songs that suit my audience.
You appreciate the oldies, right, Suzume?
Guess the rain ain't done yet...
Right, newcomer?
How did we pick up another stray?
And a huge one, at that.
Hey, a rainbow.
Now there's a good sign.
Man.
Tough crowd.
Suzume, cats don't follow people without a reason.
Unlike dogs.
Those black and white cats...
must really want something from you.
Precisely.
Wha—
Return everything as it was, with human hands.
It spoke!
Ah...hey, hey, he—
You're kidding me...
Hey, it's fixed.
Oh, come on!
That could've ended much worse.
Never mind that. Did those cats just talk?
T-They totally did, didn't they?
What the heck was that?
Supernatural stuff?
Nah, that can't be possible.
Excuse me!
They won't stop.
Serizawa!
We're about 10km out, right?
Approximately 20km to your destination.
More like 20.
It's still quite a ways away.
Return to the designated route.
I know!
I'm gonna run the rest.
Thank you so much, Serizawa!
You too, Tamaki!
I'm going too.
Thanks for getting us this far.
I think you might actually make a great teacher...
H-Hey, you guys!
What the heck was that all about?
Man, I envy you, Souta.
Tamaki?
I give up.
This is about you chasing someone you love, right?
Th-This isn't a love thing.
Hey, Suzume...
Who are these guys?
They're supposed to be gods?
Gods!?
What I said, in the parking lot...
Sure, I've felt that way at times...
But that's not the only thing I've felt.
Yeah.
You understand it's not the only thing...
Me too.
I'm sorry, Tamaki.
Your first time home in 12 years.
I'm home, Mommy!
I'm home, Mom.
Look at how much she's grown, Sis.
I have no idea what she's about to do.
Found it.
SUZUME'S IMPORTANT STUFF
A diary?
Yeah.
I don't remember exactly what happened back then.
But I do remember wandering through a door...
MARCH 11
Tsunami warning.
Those near the ocean,
please evacuate to high ground immediately.
Have you seen my mommy?
Are you alone?
She was working at the hospital.
Have you seen my mommy?
They haven't found Tsubame?
That girl's still looking today.
Do you know where my mommy is?
She's only four...
Her mother's probably—
The poor thing.
Have you seen my mommy?
She's all alone.
I'm sorry, Suzume.
My mommy...
Sorry.
Mommy!
Where are you?
It wasn't...a dream.
That's right, the moon was full that night.
Right by that telephone pole.
What?
You're looking for this door?
Hey, Suzume!
It's been 12 years! The rubble's probably long gone!
Where?!
Suzume.
Daijin?
Hey, what're...?
Daijin, have you...
Have you been guiding us to the open doors all this time?
This whole time...
Whoa!
Thank you so much, Daijin!
Let's go, Suzume!
Suzume!
Tamaki.
I'm going!
Going where?
To see the person I love!
Suzume?
The ground is on fire.
That's...
The worm!
It's going for the Gate!
Sadaijin?
Is that...
Souta!?
Daijin, you...
Suzume, are you okay?
What is this place?
This is the Ever-After?
It's Souta!
Souta!
Suzume.
If you take the Keystone,
the worm will escape.
I'll become the Keystone!
So please...
Wake up, Souta!
You...
Souta!
I've come this far!
Please, answer me!
Souta!
Let me hear your voice.
Souta!!!
Hey, you...
Do you know of any ruins in this area?
Ruins?
Are you not afraid to die!?
I'm not!
We make a great team!
I think I'm doing something pretty important!
Join us.
Well, aren't you popular, Souta?
Wait!
Is this...
Yeah.
So...
This is it...
This is where I end?
Souta's memories?
But I was able to meet you.
Souta?
Souta!
Hey! Souta!
I finally met you!
Souta!
I don't want to disappear.
I want to live!
I want to keep living!
I'm afraid to die!
I want to live.
To live...
To live.
More!
So do I!
I want to live more...
I want to hear your voice.
I don't want to be alone.
I'm afraid to die.
Souta...
Souta?
Suzume?
What was I...
Daijin?
What's wrong?
You okay?
I...
couldn't become your cat, Suzume.
Return me...
...with your hands.
Daijin...
The second Keystone!
The worm's going to escape from the Gate!
Suzume!
I'm fine.
What now?
Hear their voices, and they'll hear us.
Follow me!
O Divine Gods who dwell beneath this land...
You have long protected us for generations...
Thy mountains and rivers that we have long called our own...
We respectfully return to thee!
Morning!
Good morning!
Bon appetit!
Thanks for the food.
See you soon.
Come home soon.
See you later!
See you soon.
I'm off now.
Take care.
See you later.
Come home soon.
Don't be too late!
I'll see you soon.
Take care!
See you soon.
See you later.
I know that life is fleeting.
We live side-by-side with death.
Even then...
once more...
even for just one moment more
we wish to live!
Divine gods!
Please... Please!
I beg of you!
It's okay.
Entrust yourself.
I return to you!!
Suzume...
Suzume, there's someone here...
A child?
That girl...
I need to go!
Suzume?
I see...
That's right.
I finally understand!
Suzume.
Suzume!
Mommy?
No...
Do you know where my mommy is?
I know she's looking for me, too!
And she must be super worried!
I need to go to where she is!
Suzume, you're...
My mommy works at the hospital,
and she's really good at cooking and wood stuff.
She can make anything!
Suzume—
And my house is...
It's gone, so...
Mommy...
She just doesn't know where to look for me, so...!
That's enough!!
Deep down, I already knew...
Why?
Mommy's still out there! She's looking for me!
Suzume!
Mommy, where are you?
Mommy!!!
Mom...
What am I supposed to do?
Suzume, look.
See?
It's my chair.
Huh?
How can I say this...
You see, Suzume...
No matter how sad you are now,
you're going to grow up.
So, don't worry.
The future's not that scary.
You'll meet a lot of people you care for...
And you'll meet lots of people who'll care for you, too.
The night might seem endless right now
but one day, morning will come.
You'll grow up basking in that light.
I'm sure of it.
It's written in the stars.
Miss...
who are you?
I'm...
your tomorrow.
I completely forgot.
I'd been given everything that matters a long time ago.
Okay, I'm off!
♪ Meaning of love, the touch,
♪ the theory of relativity
♪ It all seems so unreal to me,
Suzume!
♪ like a pipe dream in my mind
Hey!
Tamaki!
Serizawa?
♪ By the time I grow up,
♪ will we ever meet?
Say, did you get your money back from Souta?
Oh, that... was a lie.
I actually owe Souta.
♪ By then, will I know the meaning of
Looks like he forgot, so...
♪ thousands of love songs?
Could you keep it between us?
You're hopeless.
♪ But love was not a revolution or frustration or catastrophe
Why don't you come back with us?
The weight of people's feelings is what quells the land.
♪ Love was you
There are still places where that's disappeared,
causing the Gates to open.
I'll close them as I return to Tokyo.
♪ The way you laughed somehow resembled loneliness
Souta! Um...
♪ The way you sang reminded me of a glow in this morning's sky
♪ Rather than humans acting thousands of years from now
Thank you for saving me.
I'll come see you. I promise.
♪ I'd love to see you laugh with a face no one knows yet
♪ What I don't have, what I don't have is what you are made of
♪ You make me who I am
♪ You're gonna laugh when I say this, right?
♪ I wanna see that face even
♪ What I don't have, what I don't have is what you are made of
♪ And who the world sings praises to
♪ "If only you were here"
♪ No matter how horrendous the words that follow may be
♪ I'll embrace those words in my arms
♪ Despair I see with you will shine brighter
than the hope without you
Welcome back.
♪ The way you laughed somehow resembled tenderness
♪ The way you sang was like today's evening rain
♪ Rather than humans acting thousands of years from now
♪ I'd love to see you laugh with a face no one knows yet
♪ What I don't have, what I don't have is what you are made of
♪ You make me who I am
♪ If I call your name out till my voice is gone
♪ And if that's what it takes to reach you,
then I will call right now
♪ Red lines, blues lines you carry inside
♪ The twain shall meet at the center of your heart
♪ In a voice that withstands the wind
♪ I'm bringing up the words to deliver
♪ Time is a sleeper, wind the soft skin,
♪ the star is a cradle, people are a mirage
♪ If this tear answers your question of why I'm crying
♪ It's not as close to the meaning of us finding each other
♪ It's the shout that this body alone will never be enough
♪ Found a heart that trembles only when I touch your hand
♪ How many meanings must we get over to be there?
♪ Could be stupidity, could be ugliness,
♪ beyond what's right, I want to hold hands with you
♪ Precious memories I can't recall
♪ These are the thoughts that can't be put into words
♪ Maybe, just maybe
♪ That's all this heart is made of
♪ It still beats your heart
♪ Wanting you to "notice me"
♪ If this tear answers your question of why I'm crying
♪ It's not as close to the meaning of us finding each other
♪ It's the shout that this body alone will never be enough
♪ Found a heart that trembles only when I touch your hand
♪ How many meanings must we get over to be there?
♪ Could be stupidity, could be ugliness,
♪ beyond what's right, I want to live with you